Raihan Akbar

Jl. Ki Hajar Dewantara, RT.2/RW.4, Mekarmukti, Kec. Cikarang Utara, Kabupaten Bekasi, Jawa Barat 17530

Mobile: +628 2177109661 Email: raihanakbar0704@gmail.com

Profile

A fourth-year Information Technology undergraduate student at President University. Experienced in designing user interactions on websites, developing servers and databases for website functionality and coding for web based applications. Interested in fundamental languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.

Education

President University

09/2020 - Present

Information Technology (S. Kom), specializing in web-development, with a current GPA of 3.68/4.00. Familiar with web design, web publishing, web programming, and database management.

Work Experience

PT. Sucofindo Indonesia Company

09/2022 - 04/2023

Full Stack Developer

President University recommended me for a position wherein my primary responsibility involves the development of website dashboards. Contribute to the field of IoT (Internet of Things) by working on sensors such as temperature and humidity detectors. As a result, the website that I developed is currently utilized to monitor the operating systems within the information and business solutions division in PT. Sucofindo Company.

Webinar Membangun Personal Branding di Era Digital 2021

07/2021

Master of Ceremony

President University conducted a Statepersonship course featuring webinars that focused on developing personal branding in the digital age. Emphasized the importance of building a professional image through the utilization of digital mediums. Responsible for provide insights on various techniques and strategies for creating a strong and positive online presence. Led the event that discusses the qualifications for students from all over Indonesia, with a total of more than 150 participants.

Academic Activity

Server-side Internet Programming Project

09/2021 - 01/2022

Project Leader of Online Web Application

At President University, I completed a course in server-side internet programming that required the development of a website interface. Responsible for developing website interfaces using HTML, CSS, PHP, and JavaScript, with database integration using MySQL and PHP. Completed course in server-side internet programming at President University.

Software Engineers Project

01/2022 - 05/2022

Participants

As part of my academic program at President University, I completed a course in the Software Engineers Project that involved the creation of multiple diagram types. Within a team environment, we utilized Figma for website design, the development of the login, home page, cart, and checkout features. Responsible for executing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript coding tasks that were integral to the project's success.

Language

Indonesian : Native Proficiency

English : Intermediate Communication English

Professional Training Program

Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Website Training

12/2021

Conducted by IEEE Student Branch Diponegoro University.